Register of the Mikhail Vladimirovich Bernatskii Miscellany, 1916-1918
Hoover Institution Archives
Mikhail Vladimirovich Bernatskii Miscellany,
1916-1918
XX078
Bernatskii, Mikhail Vladimirovich, 1876-
1 folder (0.1 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Summary: Reports, correspondence, and statistics, relating to the financing of the Russian war effort during World War I.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918--Economic aspects; World War, 1914-1918-Russia; Russia
Container List
- Monthly records of state revenue and expenditures, up to July 1917 (Folder 1.)
- List of extraordinary credits for war expense exceeding the budget scheme, up to 15 January 1918
- Report concerning the operations of credit during the war
- Note containing information about Russian State operations of credit in the United States during the war
- Secret correspondence between the Director of the Chancellery of Credit and the Financial Attachi in London with reference to the upholding rate of the rouble in Persia
- United balance of the private institutes of credit, up to 30 September, 1917
- Items referring to investment of shares societies, 1913-1917
- Telegrams of the Russian Ambassador in Washington
- Material concerning the indebtedness of Russia in foreign countries, up to 8 October 1917
- Balance of the Foreign Trade of Russia, up to 15 October 1917
- Subscription to the Liberty Loan, up to 20 September 1917
- Deposits and their movement at the State Savings-Banks, up to 19 August, 1917
- Financial Agreement between the British and Russian Governments supplementary to the agreement of 30 September, 1915 and 27 October 1916 (in English)
- Schemes of Coffee monopoly, presented by the Provisional Government of Russia, up to 20 October 1917